Juan P. Ayala Product designer

I am a native smiler who loves creating meaningful design experiences and have cooperated with fantastic and talented people in both Irish and Venezuelan companies for the past 10 years.

Proficient in visual and UX/UI design, design thinking model, data analysis, coding, reporting, English, Spanish and Portuguese.

Skills

Sketch, Adobe Suite, InVision, Balsamiq, Zeplin, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, MS Office, Heap and R programming.

Contact

- in www.linkedin.com/in/jp-ayala
- BB www.behance.net/ayalajuano
- https://uxfol.io/Ayalajuan
- ayalajuano@gmail.com
- (n) Dublin, Ireland
- **©** 083-3034668

Education

2016 - 2018

BA in graphic design Dublin Institute of Design Dublin, Ireland

2008 - 2012

BS in business administration and graphic design Nueva Esparta University Caracas, Venezuela

Certifications

2021-2022

- R Coding for data science
- Intro to web accessibility
- Heap foundations

Work Experience

UX/UI Designer

Goatpath by Software ONE, Ireland

Oct 2020 - Current

- Gather user insights and data analytics to validate, identify and inform design decisions.
- Create and share reports with stakeholders to enhance the platform's ease of use.
- Audit UX/UI and accessibility issues to create a better and more inclusive product.
- Conduct interviews and usability tests to optimize user goals and pain points.
- Assist project owners, managers, UX and global teams to optimize solutions.
- Lead LATAM UX/UI product solutions to support the roadmap's quality.
- Build HTML and Sketch prototypes for usability testing.

UX/UI Designer

ALTV Media, Ireland

Dec 2017 - Feb 2020

- Delivered app redesigns focusing on streamlining existing designs and improving usability.
- Created responsive web apps using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript based on client briefs.
- $\, \bullet \,$ Built apps based on design thinking: Empathize, define, ideate, prototype and test.
- Conducted market research, personas creation and user journeys.
- Key projects include Dugout and National Broadband Ireland.

UX/UI Designer

Meebler, Ireland

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed and developed a website as part of the product modification and relaunch.
- Expanded the company's branding and identity by creating strong visual elements.
- Carried out QA testing of the prototype app ensuring an intuitive user flow.
- Contributed to developing user personas and journeys in team workshops.
- Designed a live prototype app presented at the Dublin Tech Summit 2017.

UI Designer

Marketplace Connectors (Internship), Ireland

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Created marketing collateral, infographics and videos to develop the business initiatives.
- Led and created photographic material for social media and the company's website.
- Designed responsive, multi-device and intuitive designs for the Connect.IO platform.

Career Break

Freelancing, travelling, learning new languages.

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016

UI Developer

Servicios Netosfera, Venezuela

May 2013 - Aug 2013

- Designed, developed and maintained updates for the customer's corporate websites.
- Prepared captivating designs for clients' branding and marketing material.
- Advised clients on the development of their company's branding.

Graphic Designer

Super Eventos, Venezuela

Sep 2011 - Aug 2012

- Designed promotional material for events in line with the client's branding & identity.
- Created interactive apps to showcase event highlights for clients' senior managers.
- Designed impactful proposals and presentations for marketing events.
- Key customers include Samsung & Coca-Cola.